《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
SAM: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我实在搞不明白 在我被关押了几星期后
I can't figure it. All those weeks in detention
忽然他们就把放我出来了
and then suddenly, they let me out.
我需要造反领导们
I want a specific place, I want a specific time
每一次高级会议的具体地点和具体时间
for a very high-level meeting of the insurgency leadership.
如果我们得不到  我们会再次把少抓回来
And if I don't get it, we pick up Saul again,
而这次  他失去的就不止是一只眼睛
and this time he'll lose more than an eye.
我们必须不惜一切代价来保护这孩子
DORAL: The child's life must be protected at all costs.
第一个赛昂人与人类的混种
D'ANNA: The first Cylon-human hybrid.
这真是上帝赐予的奇迹
It truly is a miracle from God.
我们失去她了
We lost her.
我们尽力了...但她还是死了
We did the best we could, but she's dead
就这样结束了
and that's all there is to it.
她是那么美丽
She's so beautiful.
你要明白  玛雅  这次收养要绝对保密
You understand, Maya, that this adoption requires absolute secrecy.
我向你保证
You have my word.
每天都有猛禽战机
TIGH: There's a Raptor out there every day,
在外轨道监听无线电信号
listening for a wireless call,
它会在那里等着  因为那个老头子
and it's out there because the old man
不会把我们留给赛昂人
isn't just gonna leave us to the Cylons!
"我们会用这个频率每12小时联系一次"
"Will make contact this frequency every 12 hours.
"坚持住  我们来接你们了"
"Have hope. We're coming for you. "
赛昂人已经把着陆的殖民飞船上的…
The Cylons have removed launch keys
启动钥匙转移了 地点未知
from grounded Colonial ships, location unknown.
最佳选择是安排地面上的人
The best option is that Saul and the people on the ground
让他们找回原来的启动钥匙
get their hands on the original launch keys.
上将决定派些人下到地面去
DUALLA: The Admiral's decided to put some boots on the ground.
想要派一名军官下去
He wants to send an officer as a liaison
充当我们与抵抗组织之间的联络人
between us and the resistance elements
来协调救援行动
on the planet to coordinate the rescue op.
很合理  有什么问题?
It makes sense. What's the problem?
问题是派谁下去
It's who he's sending.
整个计划是一次不计后果的赌博
This entire plan is a reckless gamble.
你在拿整个人类种族冒险
You are risking the lives of the entire human race.
你应利用帕伽索斯和民用船只上的资源
You should make plans to resume the search for Earth
尽快制定寻找地球的计划
with Pegasus and the civilian fleet.
而我要回去
But I'm going back.
我们围捕那些反叛军的领袖然后公开处决他们
We round up the leaders of the insurgency and we execute them publicly.
我们在街上随便抓一些人
CAVIL: We round up at random groups
然后公开处决他们
off the street and we execute them publicly.
放出消息说刽子手来了
Send a message that the gloves are coming off.
叛乱必须立即停止
The insurgency stops now
否则我们就开始减少人口数量
or else we start reducing the human population
让人数降到一个更有利于管理的水平
to a more manageable size.
让他们出来活动一下吧
Let them stretch their legs for a minute.
好了  所有人出来
JAMMER: All right, everybody out!
所有人出来!5分钟休息
Five minute rest break!
快点
Come on, move!
你 到这来
You, over here.
跑
Run.
跑!别回头看  快
Run, don't look back. Go!
我来帮你吧!
ELLEN: Can I help you?
不
No.
这样就行了
ELLEN: There we go.
谢谢
TIGH: Thanks.
对不起         没事  这不要紧
Sorry. No, that's all right. It doesn't hurt.
我很感激你这么做
Now, I appreciate you doing this.
我从镜子看这里就是找不准地方
I can't seem to get it right in the mirror.
少
Saul.
我想让你知道
I want you to know
为了你  我可以做任何事
that I would do anything for you.
是
Yeah.
名单
The list,
凯莉在名单上  他们会杀了她的
Cally's on the list. They're gonna kill her.
什么名单?他们要杀了她?
What list? They're gonna kill her.
你到底在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我刚拿到这个
I got this.
我从处决档案上拿到这个
I got this from the dead drop,
是从管理部门的线人那里得来的
from the source in the administration.
这是张死亡名单  而凯莉的名字就在上面
It's a death list and Cally's name is on it.
他们在城市里抓人
They're rounding up people in the city
凯莉已经被逮捕了
and Cally's already in the detention.
他们随时都可以将她拉出来
They could take her out at any minute...
他们通过车辆把她运出去
They've got this organized by transport vehicles.
凯莉就在前往地图坐标X-Ray 7的那群人里
Cally's in a group heading for map coordinate X-ray-7...
我知道  但他妈的到底在哪里?
I know. Where the frak is that?
我的意思是  我们怎么才能够...
I mean, how are we gonna...
冷静下来  该死的
Calm down, damn it!
军士长  你一定要冷静思考  不然她会死掉的
You've got to start thinking clearly, here, Chief, or she's dead.
现在我们已经搞明白他们的地图坐标系统的使用方法
Now, we've already figured out their map coordinate system.
应该与你搞到的死亡档案的…
It's referred to in the list of Cylon freqs
赛昂通讯频率表有关
you got from the last dead drop.
真他妈的伟大!你说对了
Holy frak, you're right.
我能推断出坐标...
I can extrapolate the coordinate system...
押送凯莉的那队人必须…
TIGH: Cally's group has to pick up
先在城镇里集合队伍
a bunch of people in town first.
那要花费一些时间
That'll take time.
带四个人去那里  抢在那些卡车前头
Take four men and get there ahead of the trucks.
军士长  小心点!
Chief! Pull it together.
如果你也被抓了  这对她没任何好处
You won't do her any good if you get caught, too.
而且  最终  你儿子的父母只能是我和艾伦
Besides, the last thing your son wants is me and Ellen for parents.
去找到名单 军士长
Find that list, Chief.
该死的到底在哪?
Frak! Where the frak is it? I know it's...
该死!真该死!
Damn it! Gods damn it!
该死的名单到底在哪?
Where's the frakking list?
应该在这儿  应该在这儿
Okay, it's gotta be in here. It's gotta be.
我干了些什么 就是它
What did I do with it? That's it.
在这里 太好了
That's it, okay.
名单呢
Where's the list?
见鬼 快
Damn it! Come on!
在这儿 好 X-ray-7-1-4-3…
Here it is. Okay, X-ray-7-1-4-3...
嗨  军士长  这真是个散步的好日子  对吧?
Hey, Chief. Good day for a walk, huh?
把你的人集合起来
TYROL: Get two men together.
我们要去普加马斯平地
We're going to Pergamus Flats.
情况如何  格尼
Talk to me, Gunny.
不对劲  少尉
I don't like it, Eltee.
沿着这痕迹太容易中埋伏了
Too much cover along this trail.
我们会在那里...那里...还有那里 遭到扫射炮火
We could catch enfilade fire from there, there, and along there.
我们走吧
Let's move out.
我要到汇合点
I'm going to the rendezvous point.
派你的人在山脊上掩护
Place your men on the ridge for cover.
走吧  黑豹们!
Go, Panthers!
C-Bucks规则!
C- Bucks rule!
嗨  山姆  好久不见
Hey, Sam, it's been a while.
真有趣  我觉得每天都看见你似的
Funny, I feel like I see you every day.
来吧  我们走
Come on.
是那些卡车
TYROL: There's trucks.
让他下到山脊去
Tell him to move down to the ridge.
下到山脊去
Move down to the ridge.
克里斯平  听到了吗
Crispick, did you hear?
就是这里了  子弹上膛  打开保险
This is it. Lock and load.
来吧  看看我们能看到什么!
All right, what do we see?
噢  该死的
TYROL: Oh, frak me.
什么?
SEELIX: What?
他们抓了劳拉・罗丝琳  还有汤姆・查莱克
They've got Laura Roslin and Tom Zarek with them.
看到凯莉了吗?
Is there any sign of Cally?
还没有
Not yet.
卡拉狄加计划了营救任务  并即将执行
All right, so Galactica's got a rescue plan in place and ready to go.
我的任务是
My job is to get the launch keys
找到还留在地面上的民用船只的启动钥匙
for the civilian ships still on the ground
然后根据你们的撤退计划  调整营救任务
and then coordinate the rescue mission with your evacuation plan.
我们什么时候与泰上校见面?
When can we meet with Colonel Tigh?
我们要等到天黑了
We're gonna wait until nightfall
才能回到市内
before we head back into the city.
找到她了 找到她了
Oh, there she is. There she is.
噢  谢谢上帝  找到她了
Oh, my Gods, there she is.
该死的她在干吗?
What the frak's she doing?
她在想办法逃出来
She's making a run for it.
那些铁皮人排成了一列
The bulletheads are lining up.
那是攻击方队
TYROL: It's a firing squad.
瞄准那些赛昂武士  马上!
Sight in on the Centurions, right now.
凯莉在我们的攻击线上
Cally's right in the line of fire.
如果我们开火  会打伤她的
If we shoot, we're gonna hit her.
倒数5 开火
Then count to five and open fire.
有两个人形赛昂
CHEADLE: Two skin jobs.
我们要把他们干掉吗?
Should we take them down?
哪里有人形赛昂  那里就有铁皮人
MATHIAS: Where there are skin jobs, there are bulletheads.
把火箭筒拿来
Bring up the RPG.
这里有一些下水道
SAM: Now, there's a system of tunnels
我们以前用过...
we've been using that run parallel to the...
你们听到了吗?
You hear that?
快!快撤         找掩护
SAM: Go! Go! Move! MAN: Get down there!
别停留
ATHENA: Don't stay!
都出去
Everyone get out!
快 快 快
Go! Go! Go! Go!
躲到树丛后面
Get in line behind the tree line!
1001码  1002码…
One thousand one, one thousand two,
1003码...
one thousand three,
1004码...
one thousand four,
1005码
one thousand five...
低下  走
MAN 1: Get down! Go!
在树后面
MAN 2: Behind the trees!
该死的  我们要离开这里
Frak this. We've got to get out of here.
待着别动  相信我
Stay put. Trust me.
就是现在!
MATHIAS: Now.
谢谢
Thanks.
他们在等我们  中尉  就在我们约好的地方
They were waiting for us, Eltee, right where we thought.
山姆  你最好看看这个
CONNOR: Sam, you'd better take a look at this.
我在一个人形赛昂身上找到的
I found it on a dead skin job.
这是你的笔迹  对吧?
It's your handwriting, isn't it?
没错  还真他妈的是
Yeah, you're damn right it is.
我们被出卖了
SAM: We were sold out.
是艾伦
Ellen.
检查下 确保他们都没事
INSURGENT: Check them out. Make sure they're okay.
你还好吧  汤姆?
You all right, Tom?
还好
Yeah.
自从有个女人把我打倒以后
It's been a while since I had a woman throw me to the ground.
我就不认为这有多有趣了
Not quite as much fun as I remember.
很痛  对吧  太好了
It hurts, huh? Good.
那么我希望会痛很长很长时间
And I hope it hurts a long, long time
直到你重新去下载地
until you go to Download City.
你们在下面好吗?
You all right down there?
噢  天呀
Oh, my Gods!
见到你真好  军士长
It's good to see you, Chief.
我也很高兴见到你  女士
It's good to see you too, ma'am.
现在发生了什么?我们要去哪里?
What happens now? Where do we go from here?
我们要回家  我们要回家了
We're going home. We're going home.
阿达玛上将已经上路了
Admiral Adama's on his way.
我们度过这个困难时期后就要回到卡拉狄加了
We're getting off this rock, we're going back to Galactica.
别担心  盖尤斯  没事的
Don't worry about it, Gaius. It's all right.
这对我真的无所谓
It doesn't matter to me, really.
你能否马上闭嘴  行不?
You can stop that right now, okay?
我的自负还没到如此脆弱的地步
My ego's not so fragile as all that.
这些事情发生了或者他们没有发生
These things happen or they don't happen.
所以我们应该说什么好呢?
So what shall we talk about?
我们可以说说你过的日子吗?
Shall we talk about your day?
亲爱的  你的日子过得如何?
How was your day, darling?
你在办公室里的日子如何?
How was your day at the office?
我的办公室
My office.
有消息吗?
Any news?
没有
No?
好吧  那让我告诉你我过得如何
Well, let me tell you about my day,
因为过得一团糟
because it was a hoot.
我与其中一个得罗有过令人醉心的聊天
I had the most fascinating chat with one of the Dorals.
他有过一个卫生间是人类重获
He's got this theory about sanitation being the key
自信与互信的钥匙的理论
to regaining human trust and confidence,
像是与厕纸相关
something about toilet paper.
不  短缺的厕纸.就是这个
No, lack of toilet paper, that's it.
如果人们能够擦干净他们的屁股
How if people could only wipe their bums properly,
在投票时选票数量一定会有客观的增加
there'd be a measurable up-tick in the polls.
四个月了  盖尤斯
Four months of this, Gaius.
四个月以来看着你越滑越远
Four months I'm watching you slip further and further
到这般自我憎恨与厌恶的地步
down into this well of self-hatred and loathing.
你知道我为你放弃了什么吗?
Do you know what I've given up for you?
你知道吗?
Do you?
你知道吗  由于这次占领与众多事情的原因
Gee, dear, what with the occupation and everything,
我真的不能说我最近能够思考这些东西
I can't really say I've given it that much thought recently.
别走
Don't go.
求求你
Please.
那看起来也没那么糟
It doesn't look so bad.
我有些话想对你说
Hey, there's something that I wanted to say to you.
我真的很抱歉把你一个人留下来
I'm sorry that I left you alone.
我不是故意想让你受伤害
I didn't mean for you to get hurt.
我对自己很失望而不是你  可以了吧?
I was upset with myself and not you, okay?
长大的过程中往往会做一些愚蠢的事
Grown-ups do stupid things sometimes.
我们还来得及找回我们之间的小世界
We get caught up in our own little world until it's almost too late.
你完全不知道我在对你说什么  对吧?
You have no idea what I'm saying to you, do you?
好了  是时候睡觉了
Okay, time to take a nap.
别担心  我知道你是谁  你是什么
Don't be afraid. I know who you are, what you are.
可怜的东西
Poor thing.
你一定被吓坏了
You must be terrified.
你有糖吗?
Do you have any candy?
糖?
Candy?
没有
No.
粗糠柴太苦了 (译者注:粗糠柴-一种亚洲树木  结多毛)
Kamala's so bitter.
宙斯无所不知
Oh, Zeus sees all.
看见你  3号
Sees you, Number Three.
能了解你的痛苦
Sees your pain,
你的命运
your destiny.
所有神会都为你哭泣的
All the Gods weep for you.
但宙斯不会  除了上帝  没有其他的神
There is no Zeus. No other God but God.
看来  你已经不再相信了
Well, you don't believe that anymore.
你不知道你的信仰是什么 这也是你来到这里的原因
You don't know what you believe and that is why you're here.
不是这样的
It's not true.
我甚至不知道我为何要来这里
I don't even know why I'm here.
这是我干过的最蠢的事
This is the stupidest thing I ever did.
是你的梦把你带到我这里
It is your dream that brings you to me.
你是怎么知道的?
How do you know about that?
我在你所信仰的神那里得到了一条给你的信息
I have a message for you from the one you worship.
他通过我与你谈话
He speaks through me to you,
正如他在你的梦里说的那样
just as he speaks in your dreams.
那条信息是...
The message is,
两个人的(爱情)之果还活在世上
the fruit born of two peoples is alive.
一个以全知的宙斯的
A child named after the wife and sister
妻子和姐妹名字命名的孩子
of the all-knowing Zeus,
赫拉还活着 (译者注:赫拉是宙斯的妻子)
Hera, lives.
那不是真的
It's not true.
孩子死了
The child is dead.
你会把她抱在怀里的
You will hold her in your arms
而你也会第一次知道
and you'll know for the first time
什么才是真爱的感觉
what it is to feel true love,
但你会失去你在这里的所有一切
but you'll lose everything you've done here.
真希望我能有一些巧克力糖
Wish I had some chocolate caramels.
我们走吧!  在下面还有一些兄弟在等我们
Let's move! We've got some people waiting for their ride down there!
你能否不再那样看我?
Will you quit looking at me like that?
我怎样看你了?
Like what?
你知道你是怎样看我的
You know "like what. "
就像我们将要永别了那样
Like we're never gonna see each other again?
我们会再见面的  这是个好计划  杜
We will. It's a good plan, Dee.
保护好上将
Take care of the Admiral.
保护好他的儿子
Take care of his son.
各就各位  兄弟们  你们都知道的
HELO: All right, people, you know how this works.
帕伽索斯船员站在这条线左边
Pegasus crew on the port side of the line,
卡拉狄加的站在右边
Galactica on the right.
他们的敌人决意将他们分开
RACETRACK: "Their enemies will divide them,
他们的家园在炽热的火焰中毁灭
"their colonies broken in the fiery chasm of space.
他们明亮的天空被漫漫长夜所替代
"Their shining days renounced by a multitude of dark sacrifices.
但他们将永远在一起
"Yet still they will remain, always together. "
永不分开
ALL: Always together.
集结点见
CREWMAN 1: See you at the rendezvous point.
保重
CREWMAN 2: You'd better.
坚持住我们会…
CREWMAN 3: Hang onto this until we get out of this...
我会回来的
CREWMAN 4: I'll be back before you know it.
那边见 兄弟
CREWMAN 5: See you on the other side, man.
我会等你回来
CREWMAN 6: I'll hold you to that.
回头见…
CREWMAN 7: I'll see you.
CREWMAN 8: I'll see you...
上帝保佑
CREWMAN 9: May the Gods...
这是你第三次看手表了
That's the third time you've taken a look at your watch.
有约会?
Got dinner plans?
没有  我只是在想...
No, I'm just...
莎伦现在应该在地面上了
I was just thinking Sharon's probably on the ground by now.
我知道
I know.
这是你的命令
These are your orders.
你会找到汇合点的
You'll find the rendezvous point there.
带上这些平民船只 等我18小时
Take the civilian fleet, wait for me for 18 hours.
如果18小时后我没回来  那就去找地球
If I'm not back in 18 hours, then find Earth.
好吧
Yeah, right.
我会在汇合点和你见面的
I'll see you at the rendezvous point.
18小时后  尽量别迟到了
Eighteen hours. Try not to be late.
我越来越老了  也越来越迟钝了
I'm getting old and I'm a little slow.
但我会赶到的
But I'll be there.
老天  我真希望我能说服你别去
Gods, I wish I could talk you out of this.
你办不到
You can't.
你试过了
You tried.
你知道吗  老爸...
You know, Dad...
别说了
Don't.
别让我在自己的停机坪上大哭
Don't make me cry on my own hangar deck.
我会在那见到你的
See you there.
请允许离开你的船  上将
Permission to leave your ship, Admiral.
请求批准  指挥官
Permission granted, Commander.
立正!
Attention!
帕伽索斯指挥官 出发
Commander of Pegasus, departing.
18小时后
Eighteen hours.
嗨  杰克  嗨  杰克
Hey, Jake. Hey, Jake.
你不关心我是谁  对吗?
Yeah, you don't care who I am, do you?
我们在你眼中都是神的子民
We're all God's creatures in your eyes.
对吗
Here you go.
好小子      睡不着?
Good boy. Can't sleep?
恶梦
Bad dreams.
还不知道你这类人也会做梦
I didn't know you people had dreams.
当然
Oh, sure.
每个人都会做梦  医生
Yeah, everybody dreams, Doc.
那是人类还是赛昂人的血?
Is that human or Cylon blood?
赛昂人
Cylon.
今天  其中一个5号被起义军漂亮地击中了
One of the Fives got pretty shot up today by the insurgents.
但他能撑过来
He's gonna make it.
你可以让他好好地享受下痛苦
You could have let him suffer.
那不是我要做的
It's not what I do.
那个婴儿又如何?
What about the baby?
莎伦的孩子 赫拉
Sharon's baby, Hera?
当那个小孩在卡拉狄加死去的时候
When that child died on Galactica,
你为何火化了尸体?
why did you cremate the body?
那是第一个人类与赛昂人的混血儿
It's the first Cylon-human hybrid
而你却把她扔进了焚化炉
and you threw it in the incinerator?
不是我做的决定
Oh, it wasn't my decision.
是总统的要求
That was the president's call.
我只是遵守命令而已
I was just following orders.
这真是很有意思
That's a very funny thing.
这些玩意看起来一模一样
Because this stuff all looks the same.
她说
She said,
"那么我希望会痛很长很长时间  直到你重新去下载地"
"I hope it hurts you for a long, long time before you go to Download City. "
然后他们就离开了我
And then they just left me there.
他们就在烈日下  留下了中弹的我
They left me in the hot sun with a bullet in my guts.
多么高尚的种族呀!
What a noble race you are.
在你死之前  在那待了多久?
BOOMER: How long were you there before you died?
几个小时
CAVIL: Hours.
后来  我设法
Eventually, I managed to drag myself
翻身找到一些弹片
over to some spent shell casings
我用其中一片割断了我的颈动脉
and I used one of those to scratch open my carotid artery.
皮肤比你们想象的要坚韧得多
Skin is a lot tougher than you think.
现在...这是我的第三次下载
Now that's three for me, three downloads.
第一次  我只是被爆了头但我还能忍受
The first one I just got a headache, but I could handle it.
现在  越来越糟了
Now it's worse and worse.
现在的感觉
This time it was like
就像该死的烧红了的铁棒穿过我的头骨
a frakking white-hot poker through my skull.
不值得  完全不值得
It's not worth it. None of this is worth it.
他是对的  你知道
He's right, you know.
不值得
It's not worth it,
这就是我一直以来告诫你们的  我所相信的
which is what I believe I've been telling you all along.
卡布里卡  你能让他闭嘴吗?
Caprica, can you please control him...
你何不向我开枪
Why don't you just shoot me
如果那样能改变现状
if that would remedy the situation?
我们需要更强硬的措施
DORAL: We need to crack down harder.
怎么做?
How?
我们已经无计可施了
Our resources are stretched to the max already.
我不想再听这些了
I don't need to listen to this anymore.
以前我们通常是很容易达成一致的
Consensus used to be so easy.
但现在看看它们都给我们带来了什么?
Now look what they've done to us.
不要失去希望
But don't lose hope.
如果情况越来越糟 我们可以用核武器攻击并摧毁城市
Worse comes to worst, we can always nuke the city and be done with it.
最好将那牌子留下
You'd better leave those dog-tags here.
他们一看到  就知道你是谁了
If they spot them, they'll know who you are.
不  你不知道我为这玩意付出了多少努力
No. You have no idea how hard I worked for these.
我们估计启动钥匙最有可能
So, our best guess puts the launch keys
被放在了拘留所的某处
somewhere in the detention center.
你最好沿在主街道走
Now just keep to the main streets, okay?
所有人都认为你只不过是一个普通的人形赛昂
Everybody will think you're just a regular skin job
他们会避开你
and they'll avoid you,
但也有很多人会乘机
but there's a lot of people out there looking
干掉一个闲逛着的毫无防备的赛昂人
to gut an unwary Cylon going for a stroll,
所以  别让任何人靠近到足以捅你一刀的地方
so don't let anybody get close enough to stick a knife in you.
好的  谢谢提醒
All right, thanks for the concern.
这让我不知所措
Makes me feel all warm and fuzzy inside.
你准备怎样找到那些启动钥匙?
How are you gonna find those launch keys?
我混进去后  接入数据流
When I get inside and hook into the data stream,
就能知道位置了
it'll feed me the location.
一旦我拿到钥匙  你需要将他们分发到那些
And once I get the keys, you need to distribute them to the pilots
能将那些飞船飞走的机师手里
who can fly those ships out of here.
我们已经准备好了  机师们都在等着
We're already on it. We've got pilots standing by.
安德斯    嗨…
CONNOR: Anders? MAN: Hey...
进来吧
SAM: Yeah, come in.
天呀!  她在这里干什么
My Gods, what is she doing here?
把她带下去
Get her down below
关起来  直到审讯她
and you keep her there until after the next briefing.
等会
ELLEN: Wait a minute.
不要  不要  等等  听我说  我可以解释
No, no. No, wait. Listen to me please. I can explain...
我建议你把嘴巴闭上
SAM: Now, I suggest you keep your mouth shut.
我丈夫在哪?
ELLEN: Where is my husband?
我要和我丈夫说话
I want to speak to my husband.
康纳  我们走吧     带她下去
SAM: Connor, let's go. Get her down.
来吧
Come on.
好了  我走了
Okay, I'm out of here.
等等  莎伦
SAM: Wait, Sharon...
什么事?
Yeah.
帮我个忙  留意下星芭
Do me a favor and just keep an eye out for Starbuck.
我不知道她是生是死
I don't know if she's alive or if she's dead,
已经有4个月没见到她了
but it's been four months.
我会尽力的
I'll do what I can.
谢谢
Yeah.
你们要不惜一切把这孩子藏好
ROSLIN: You must keep the child hidden at all costs.
我们让她与其他重要目标一起走
SAM: We keep her on the move, along with other high-value targets.
她不会在同一地方待
She'll never stay in any one location
超过2到3天
longer than two or three days.
山姆  我要你认真听我说
Sam, I need you to really hear me on this.
非常认真地
Really.
这里没有人  没有任何人比玛雅和她的小孩更重要
There is no one, no one, of higher value than Maya and her child.
我们不能让他们落入赛昂人手中
We cannot let them fall into Cylon hands.
我知道了
I get it.
你想让我走多远?
How far do you want me to go?
我意思是  如果有赛昂人要来抓她的迹象
I mean, if it looks like the Cylons are gonna capture them...
不
No,
别让事情发展到这一步 就这么多了
don't let it get to that point. That's all.
我不指望你告诉我这个中原由是什么
I don't suppose you're gonna tell me what this is all about.
我意思是  这孩子有多重要
I mean, what's so important about this kid?
她在将来可能十分重要
She may very well be the shape of things to come.
也许是祝福  也可能是诅咒
That's either a blessing or a curse.
我知道
I know.
我们已经在整个城市的要地
TYROL: We've stored arms and munitions
储备了武器与军需品
at key areas throughout the city.
我可以些提供迫击炮和火箭筒
MATHIAS: I can supplement that with mortars, RPGs,
和猛禽机上的一些肩扛式防空导弹
even a few shoulder-mounted anti-aircraft missiles aboard the Raptor.
很好
Great.
当信号发出时  我们的人就开始攻击机场
So, when we give the signal, our people are gonna attack the airbase,
拘留中心 电站
the detention center, the power station,
还有其他关键设施
and other critical facilities.
这个计划就是要在卡拉狄加与帕伽索斯到达时
The plan is to sow as much chaos and confusion as possible
尽可能制造混乱
the moment Galactica and Pegasus arrive.
那能够帮助掩护撤退
That should help cover the evacuation.
不会有帕伽索斯  只有卡拉狄加
No Pegasus. Just Galactica.
为什么?为什么没有帕伽索斯?发生了什么?
Why? Why no Pegasus? What happened?
不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
那已超出了我的职务范围
Way beyond my pay grade.
你们的撤退计划是什么?
What about your evac plan?
我们已经任命与分配了500名队长
We've designated and assigned 500 block captains
覆盖在城市的每一个角落
to cover each sector of the city.
每一个分队长均负责集中
Each block captain is responsible
并引导他(她)负责区域内的人们
for rallying and guiding the people
乘坐指定飞船按即定路线撤离
in his or her sector along their escape route to their designated ship.
你们不会已经演习过了吧?
I don't suppose you've been able to rehearse any of this?
是的  我们已经进行过3次模拟演习
Indeed. We've had three full dress rehearsals
在各类情况下
under the guise of fire and natural disaster drills.
但实际操作时  一定会有很多不同
MATHIAS: It'll be different when the balloon goes up.
爆炸  枪击  混乱  一定会出现很多恐慌
Explosions, shooting, chaos, there's gonna be some panic out there.
他们能做好的  这些人都知道重点
ROSLIN: They'll do fine. These people know that at some point,
他们有责任拯救他们自己
they're gonna have to be responsible for saving themselves.
我们所要做的就是做好准备  并祈祷一切顺利
All we need to do is be ready and hope for the best.
玛雅和伊西斯怎样了?
What about Maya and Isis?
我会处理的
I'm on it.
我会派两个最好的射手到那里
I've got my two best shooters here,
给他们作警卫
they're gonna be their escorts
确保他们能回到船上
and make sure they get back to the ship.
先生们  我无法告诉你们为什么
Gentlemen, I can't tell you why, but it is imperative
但让这个女人和她的小孩离开这颗星球十分要紧
that this woman and her child get off this planet.
我相信你  因为我信任他
I trust you because I trust him.
是 女士
Yes, ma'am.
少
Saul!
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
烤面包机!
RESIDENT: Toaster.
她出卖了我们
SAM: She sold us out.
你到底在说些什么?    那是谎话
What are you talking about? That's a lie.
我们在汇合点遭到埋伏
We were ambushed at the rendezvous.
赛昂人确切知道我们所在的位置
The Cylons knew exactly where we were gonna be.
不可能是艾伦     我什么也没干
Well, that doesn't mean Ellen... I didn't do anything!
这是那张地图  上校!  我画给你的那张
This is the map, Colonel! The map that I drew for you.
在你帐篷里给你的那张
I gave this to you in your tent.
你本应该烧掉它 但你的老婆出现了  帮你做了这事
You were gonna burn it, but then your wife offered to do it for you.
我从一个死去的人形赛昂伏兵身上得到的
I got it off a dead skin job at the ambush.
完全一样
Do the math!
我想解释  少
I want to explain, Saul...
该死的叛徒!  闭上你的臭嘴
Gods-damn traitor... Shut your frakking mouth!
他说...
He said...
他说他会杀了你的 谁说的!
He said he'd kill you. Who said it?
其中一个卡维尔
One of the Brother Cavils.
我是为了你才做的  少
I did it for you, Saul.
全是为了你  我不得不做
It was all for you, I had to.
我别无选择
I didn't have any choice.
你难道看不出来吗?
Don't you see that?
378号抽屉
Drawer 378.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
噢  天呀  是你
Oh, my God, it's you.
你背叛了你的人民
You're betraying your own people.
为了什么?
For what?
我现在是殖民地军官了
I'm a Colonial Officer now.
你不是他们的一员
You're not one of them.
我向他们保证过
I gave them my word.
那承诺没有价值
Now that's not what counts.
对于那些人
It's who you give it to.
我现在必须要杀了你
I'm gonna have to shoot you now.
赫拉还活着
Hera lives.
什么?
What?
你的女儿赫拉还活着
Your daughter Hera is alive.
你的新朋友没告诉你?
Didn't your friends tell you that?
他们骗你说她死了  他们把她藏了起来
They faked her death and they hid her from you.
随你怎么说
You would say anything.
不 我有过梦
No, I had dreams.
奇怪的梦
I had strange dreams.
我也有过奇怪的梦让我质疑我的信念
I was having strange dreams that made me question my faith,
让我质疑上帝
made me question God.
在那些梦里  有一个人类先知
And in the dreams there was a human oracle,
于是我去见了Dodona Selloi
so I went to see Dodona Selloi.
我不会杀你的
I'm not gonna kill you,
但我会打伤你  让你无法通知其他人
but I'm gonna wound you so you can't warn the others.
那个先知说 两个人的(爱情)之果
The oracle said that the fruit born of two peoples
还活在世上
is still alive,
就是赫拉还活着 而且如果我亲手抱起她
that Hera lives and I would hold her in my arms
我就能知道什么是真爱
and I would know true love.
把枪放下
Put down the gun
在我找到她时  你也可以抱着她
and when I find her, you can hold her, too.
阿达玛不会骗我的
Adama wouldn't lie to me.
你错了 你错了!
You're wrong. You're wrong!
启动钥匙看起来并没有被毁
The launch keys don't seem to have been damaged.
从数据点上得知
And from all the data points,
看来所有船都还有足够的燃料
it looks like the ships all still have enough tylium
至少能让他们跳跃一次
to make at least one jump.
顺便恭喜你
Congratulations, by the way.
我听说是个男孩
I heard it's a boy.
噢  他叫什么?
What's his name?
尼古拉斯  以凯莉祖父名字命名
Nicholas, after Cally's grandfather.
嘿  军士长
Hey, Chief,
你记得帮西洛撒赫拉的骨灰的时候吗?
you know when you helped Helo spread Hera's ashes?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
你真的见到骨灰了吗?
You actually saw the ashes?
当然  怎么了?
Yeah, of course. Why?
没什么
Nothing.
记得告诉凯莉  千万别让她的孩子离开她的视线
Just make sure Cally never lets her kid out of her sight.
长官 刚跳跃回来的猛禽机带回的消息
Sir, the listening Raptor just jumped back.
莎伦拿到了启动钥匙
Sharon's got the launch keys.
形势推演室  我是赛道
Rec room, Racetrack.
非常好  长官
Very well, sir.
出发了
It's on.
我是上将
This is the Admiral.
你们都听说了
You've heard the news.
你们也知道了任务
You know the mission.
你们也该知道这次任务只能以一种方式结束
You should also know there's only one way that this mission ends,
那就是从新卡布里卡成功营救
and that's with the successful rescue of our people
我们的人民
off of New Caprica.
看看你们周围
Look around you.
看看那些站在你们身边的
Take a good look at the men and women
男女们
that stand next to you.
记住这些面孔
Remember their faces.
因为会有一天  你将告诉你的子孙们
For one day you will tell your children and your grandchildren
你们曾与这些有史以来
that you served with such men and women
最出色的人共事过
as the universe has never seen.
你们一起成就了这次伟绩
And together, you accomplished a feat
你们的事迹将被世代传颂
that will be told and retold down through the ages
并且这会是众神唯一知道的
and find immortality,
不朽的壮举
as only the Gods once knew.
我以与你们共事为荣 祝作战成功
I'm proud to serve with you. Good hunting.
开始跳跃程序
Begin jump prep.
作战岗位
Action stations.
全船一级戒备
HELO: Set Condition One throughout the ship.
准备进行战斗跳跃
Stand by for combat jump.